Peiran Wang (王沛 然)

Grade: Third(3rd) Year of Bachelor Degree | Gender: Male | Location: Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China

Email:whilebug@qq.com | Phone:+86-17883693551 | Personal Web:www.whilebug.com

Education Experiences				
09/2018-Present	Sichuan University(985/211) http://scu.edu.cn/, Chengdu, China			
	School of Cyber Science and Engineering (CSE) Cyberspace security Major			
	Cyberspace security Excellent Talent Class (Special selected class)			
	GPA:3.90/4.00 Compulsory Score:90.72 (Rank 2/172 in my major in the first 5 semesters)			
Awards and Honors				
2018-2019	Annual National Scholarship (for top 2% students)			
2018-2019	Annual Sichuan University First Class Scholarship			
2019-2020	Annual Sichuan University Third Class Scholarship			
2020-2020	Third prize Annual National Mathematical Modeling Competition in Sichuan			
2019-2019	Third prize Annual National Mathematics Competition in Sichuan			
2019-2020	Elite Top 100 Competition Elite Top 100 Award			
2020-2021	National-Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program Participants			
2020-2021	Provincial -Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program Participant			
2021-2021	Internet + competition school-level second prize			
2021-2021	Internet + competition school-level golden prize			
Research Experiences				
11/2020 - 04/2021	Prof. Beibei Li's Group (https://li-beibei.github.io/), Sichuan University			
	A Framework for Solving non-IID Problems in Federated Learning			
	♦ Proposed A solution to the problem of non-IID data in Federated Learning;			
	♦ Paper accepted by <u>IEEE GlobeCom2021(CCF-C)</u> ;			
11/2020 - 06/2021	Prof. Beibei Li's Group (https://li-beibei.github.io/), Sichuan University			
	Byzantine Clients Detection in Federated Learning (Extensive version on proceeding version)			
	Proposed a method to detect and prevent Byzantine nodes in Federated Learning;			
	Paper accepted by <u>ISCC 2021 (CCF-C) Second author(Supervisor first author)</u> ;			
	♦ Extensive paper is submit to <u>ACM TIFS(CCF-A) First student author</u> ;			
04/2020 - 02/2021	Prof. Cheng Huang's Group (https://chenghuang.org/), Sichuan University			
	Javascript Cryptojacking Detection in Web Browser			
	♦ Proposed a static detection method to detect malicious mining JavaScript code in browser;			
	♦ Paper submitted to <u>IEEE TrustCom2021(CCF-C) First author, transferred to IEEE CSE</u> ;			
Program Experiences				
03/2021 - 06/2021	Prof. Beibei Li's Group (https://li-beibei.github.io/), Sichuan University			
	IoT Privacy-Enhancing Platform			
	♦ Developed a privacy protection platform to deal with the leakage of user privacy and IO			
	environment privacy;			

As the team leader, he led the research and development of the project team, which improved

Prepared to participate in the 2021 information security competition national competition /

his project management organization ability and presentation ability;

China University student computer design competition / "Internet+" Competition;

11/2019 - 2020/11

Prof. Cheng Huang's Group (https://chenghuang.org/), Sichuan University

Domestic system terminal situation awareness platform based on machine learning

- ♦ Developed an operating system attack detection system based on machine learning;
- ♦ As the team leader, he led the research and development of the project team, which improved the project management organization ability and presentation ability;
- **♦** Top 100 elites Award in 100 Elites Competition 2020;

11/2020 - 06/2021

Prof. Xinjian Xu's Group, School of literature and journalism, Sichuan University

Reconstruction of cultural memory - An Anthropological Study of Li Jieren's "Dahe Trilogy"

- ♦ Analyze project usage statistics in the project;
- ♦ Rated as National-Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program of Sichuan University in 2021;

11/2020 - 06/2021

Prof. Qilin Cao's Group, School of Business&School of Mathematics, Sichuan University

Research on the frequency of automatic rebalancing of intelligent investment advisers-Based on the analysis of Shanghai and Shenzhen data and user portraits

- Studied the rebalancing frequency of intelligent investment advisers, and proposes a method to calculate the rebalancing frequency of intelligent investment advisers;
- ♦ As a team member, he was responsible for the construction and implementation of artificial intelligence model;
- ♦ Rated as Provincial-Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program of Sichuan University in 2021;

11/2020 - 06/2021

Prof. Xuefeng Hu's Group, omaterial Engineering Research Center, Sichuan University;

soft-pain:Leader in the field of pain relief with flexible electronic materials

- ♦ Design a flexible electronic material device which can adaptively eliminate user's pain;
- ♦ As a team member, responsible for the design and construction of federal learning model;
- ♦ Rated as Provincial-Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program of Sichuan University in 2021;
- ♦ Internet + competition school-level second prize;

11/2020 - 06/2021

Wei Yin&Dan Xiao, West China School of Stomatology, Sichuan University

MothSeeker: Your intimate mothproof housekeeper

- ♦ Designs an equipment and a program which can automatically find cavities;
- ♦ As a team member, responsible for the development of wechat applet;
- ♦ Rated as National-Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program of Sichuan University in 2021;
- ♦ Internet + competition school-level second prize;

06/2020 - 06/2021

Enterprise training, Sichuan University;

Baselinecheck Platform

- A platform is developed to scan the host for baseline configuration non-compliance;
- ♦ As the team leader, manage project development and develop project interfaces;
- ◆ 2021年 Course design project of School of Cyberspace Security, Sichuan University, with a score of 95(the highest score among all the students);

11/2020 - 00/2021

Publication

- 1. MineDetector: JavaScript Browser-side Cryptomining Detection using Static Methods (First author, accepted by IEEE CSE 2021)
- 2. FedVANET: Efficient Federated Learning with Non-IID Data for Vehicular Ad Hoc Networks (Accepted by <u>IEEE GlobeCom</u> <u>2021 CCF-C</u>)
- 3. FLPhish: Reputation-Based Phishing Byzantine Defense in Ensemble Federated Learning (Second author, supervisor is first author (Accepted by <u>IEEE ISCC CCF-C)</u>
- 4. Defending Against Byzantine Attacks in Ensemble Federated Learning: A Bayesian Reputation-based Phishing Approach (Submitted to IEEE TIFS CCF-A)

Research Interest

- AI security: Federated Learning Security/Non-IID in Federated Learning/Inference Attack in AI/Poison Attack in AI
- Data-driven security:Malicious Code Analysis/Cyber Crime/Underground Economy/Social Computing

Language Skills			
01/2019	CET-4	Listening:228 Reading:180 Writing&Translation:191	Total:599
09/2019	CET-6	Listening:208 Reading:202 Writing&Translation:130	Total:540
01/2021	IELTS	Reading: 8.5 Listening: 8.5 Saying: 5.5 Writing: 6.5	Total : 7.5
Grasped Skills			

Research Skills: Deep Learning/Program Management(git)/Database Deployment(mysql)/Data Mining/Data Analysis

Preferred Programming Languages: C/Python/JavaScript/HTML/Matlab/Assembly Language

Professional Skills: SQL Injection/CSRF Attack/XSS Attack/Traffic Analysis/Reverse Engineering/Pwn/Malicious Code Analysis

Biography

After entering Sichuan University, he was selected as the member of Cyberspace Security excellence class of Sichuan University. In the first academic year, he won the national scholarship and the annual first-class scholarship of Sichuan University. In the usual course, he actively answered the teacher's questions, participated in classroom interaction. In the first five semesters, his compulsory grade ranked 2/172, with an average score of 90.72 and GPA of 3.89. He performs well in English, with IELTS score of 7.5, and can communicate with native speakers fluently. He also has rich project experiences, including a national-level undergraduate innovation and entrepreneurship project in 2020-2021 and a provincial-level undergraduate innovation and entrepreneurship project. He has many research experiences and began to participate in scientific research in his sophomore year. One EI conference paper has been received and three papers are being submitted. He is full of enthusiasm for network security research.